

Abdullah Yusefi

PhD in Sensor fusion and Visual-based Localization in Autonomous Systems. • 4.0+ yrs. of hands-on experience with 3D/2D LiDAR, 4D/3D Radar, Inertial sensors, RTK GNSS and Mono/Stereo Cameras. • Developed and implemented software for autonomous navigation, perception, and control systems in robotics.

EDUCATION

PhD, Computer Science Engineering Turkish Language Preparation	Faculty of Engineering Selcuk TÖMER	Konya Technical University, Turkey Selcuk University, Turkey	Sep 2017 – Jan 2024 Sep 2016 – Aug 2017
Masters, Computer Science Engineering	University College of Engineering	Osmania University, India	Sep 2012 – Dec 2014
Bachelor of Computer Science	Faculty of Computer Science	Kabul University, Afghanistan	Sep 2008 – Nov 2011
CERTIFICATIONS			
Build Basic Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)	Coursera	Credential ID: ESJYTWRAT64N	Dec 2020
Neural Networks and Deep Learning	Coursera	Credential ID: 7TBHQGVPUZCR	Dec 2020
Coding for Everyone: C and C++ Specialization	Coursera	Credential ID: AWWVL8PS6FMG	Nov 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

R&D Software Engineer – Robotics & Autonomous Vehicles, MPG Machinery Production Group Inc. Konya, Turkey May 2021 - Cont.

- Develop and implement software for autonomous navigation, perception, and control systems in robotics.
- Integrate visual, LiDAR, and IMU sensors for real-time environment perception.
- Apply machine learning for optimizing decision-making in dynamic environments.
- Use simulation tools to validate robotic algorithms in various scenarios.
- Collaborate with multidisciplinary teams to integrate software into complete robotic systems.
- Prepare technical documentation to communicate complex concepts effectively.
- Mentor junior team members and fostered a collaborative team environment.
- Stay updated with advancements in robotics and software engineering.

NOC Supervisor, RANA Technologies Enterprises (RTE)

Kabul, Afghanistan Feb 2015 - Aug 2016

- Oversee customer requests and promptly handle service events.
- Address escalated issues for timely resolution.
- Manage trouble ticket procedures, serving as an escalation point for NOC employees.
- Supervise phone queues, ticket statuses, and core network maintenance, demonstrating self-management, logical thinking, and strong communication skills.

IP Backbone Engineer, Afghan Wireless Communication Company (AWCC)

Kunduz, Afghanistan Dec 2011 - Aug 2012

- Install and configure Cisco networking equipment for optimal functionality.
- Monitor and maintain IP/VoIP/VPN networks to ensure reliability and high performance.
- Manage configurations, including backup, restoration, and modifications.
- Analyze syslogs, manage alarms, implement QoS for efficient bandwidth, oversee network management, troubleshoot issues, and ensure timely resolutions.

SKILLS

Language: C++, Python Framework: ROS 1/2, OpenCV Machine Learning: Keras, PyTorch OS: Linux, Windows Sensor: Camera, LiDAR, Radar, IMU, GNSS

PUBLICATIONS

A Unified Monocular Vision-Based Driving Model for Autonomous Vehicles with Multi-Task Capabilities		
IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles, IEEE	URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/10721282/	
A Generalizable D-VIO and Its Fusion with GNSS/IMU for Improved Autonomous Vehicle Localization		
IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles, IEEE	URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/10254363	
Narrow Space Warning and Slope Control System compatible with ADAS		
2023 SIU, IEEE	URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/10223997	
Improved Dead Reckoning Localization using IMU Sensor		
2022 ISETC, IEEE	URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/10010239	
HVIOnet: A deep learning based hybrid visual-inertial odometry approach for unmanned aerial system position estimation		
Neural Networks, Pergamon	URL: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0893608022003355	
COVID-19 Isolation Control Proposal via UAV and UGV for Crowded Indoor Environments: Assistive Robots in the Shopping Malls		
Frontiers in public health, Frontiers Media SA	URL: https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpubh.2022.855994/full	
The YTU dataset and recurrent neural network based visual-inertial odometry		
Measurement, Elsevier	URL: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0263224121008198	
A tutorial: Mobile robotics, SLAM, bayesian filter, keyframe bundle adjustment and ROS applications		Jul 18, 2021
Robot Operating System (ROS), Springer	URL: https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-75472-3_7	
Performance comparison of Extreme Learning Machines and other machine learning methods on WBCD data set		
2021 SIU, IEEE	URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9477984	
LSTM and Filter Based Comparison Analysis for Indoor Global Localization in UAVs		
IEEE Access, IEEE	URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9316698	

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Turkish (Fluent)
 Persian (Native)

Uzbek (Native)

• English (Excellent)